Exam day - what do you do?
考试日——你会做些什么呢？
I take a ring my grandfather gave me to the exam.
我会带着爷爷给我的一枚戒指去参加考试。
It's a reminder of his affection and gives me a sense of security and calms my nerves.
它是爷爷关爱的一种提醒，能给我一种安全感，让我放松下来。
My brother makes a fuss about wearing his green underwear.
我的哥哥会小题大做穿上他的绿色内裤。
He's not alone in placing his hopes in a garment.
并非只有他一个人把希望寄托在一件衣物上。
One in three students admitted to wearing 'good luck underwear' to try to boost exam chances, according to a poll for pen makers, Bic.
根据钢笔制造商比克（Bic）开展的一项民意调查，三分之一的学生承认会穿“幸运内裤”，试图提高考试通过的几率。
The same poll suggested that 60% of students change their diet before a test in the hope that it can increase their brain power and memory – oily fish and fruit and vegetables are at the top of the list.
同一项民意调查显示，60%的学生在考试前会改变饮食，希望能提高他们的脑力和记忆力——富含脂肪的鱼以及水果和蔬菜在他们的饮食清单中位居前列。
This is good as long as you don't stuff your face with junk food all year long and decide to go healthy just for the exam.
只要你不是一整年都狂吃垃圾食品，只是为了考试才决定吃得健康些，这样做还是不错的。
Making the extra effort to succeed is good but if you haven't put in the hours of study, nothing will help you.
为取得成功付出额外努力是好的，但如果你没有投入学习时间，什么都帮不了你。
Patrick Wilson, former teacher and founder of a private tuition firm, says: "The best way to feel truly confident and help beat that stomach-churning exam angst is to prepare for each exam in advance, making sure you have a dedicated structure for your revision schedule."
前教师、一家私人辅导公司的创始人帕特里克・威尔逊（Patrick Wilson）说：“要真正感到自信并克服那种令人反胃的考试焦虑，最好的办法是提前为每场考试做好准备，确保你有一个专门的复习计划表。”
Wilson helped to create a guide for avoiding the last-minute jitters.
威尔逊协助编写了一份避免临考紧张的指南。
It advises the revision timetable to start up to ten weeks before the exam, dividing learning into chunks.
该指南建议复习时间表要在考试前十周就开始制定，将学习内容分成组块。
Don't overload yourself.
不要给自己过多负担。
Students should also give themselves regular rewards and breaks during revision.
学生们在复习期间也应该定期给自己一些奖励和休息时间。
People learn things in different ways and this should be taken into account.
人们学习的方式各不相同，这一点应该被考虑进去。
I learn better by reading things out loud.
通过大声朗读，我的学习效果会更好。
Some colleagues believe colour-coordinating notes according to subject can produce good results too.
一些同事认为，按照科目用适当的颜色记笔记也能取得不错的效果。
But there's a consensus against spending the night before the exam studying.
但大家有一个共识，就是反对在考试前一晚学习。
If you don't get enough sleep, not even good luck underwear will help you pass the test.
如果你睡眠不足，即使是穿幸运内裤也无法帮你通过考试。